



"Success is the sum of small efforts repeated day in and day out."
- Robert Collier

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

My passion began many years ago with web design and evolved into a curiosity for how to "build stuff". I love being immersed in the programming world and am seeking a Junior Developer or internship opportunity. I am dedicated to learning my craft and would love to contribute to a team while building upon my current skill set.

Skills include:

Full-Stack Web Development, Object-Oriented Programming / Test Driven Development / Digital Project Management / Online Marketing Collateral / Graphic Design

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Software / Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, Middleman, WordPress, Photoshop

EDUCATION

The Firehose Project, 2015

Full-Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails

Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY, 2003-2007

Martin J. Whitman School of Management

Bachelor of Science; Entrepreneurship & Emerging Enterprises

Dean's List

EXPERIENCE

The Firehose Project, Remote, June 2015 - Present

Full-Stack Web Developer Apprentice

Build web applications using Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, Test Driven Development, Git, GitHub, AWS, and Heroku. Solve Ruby coding challenges (algorithms and data structures).

Biz Dev Now, Remote, March 2014 - Present

Digital Project Manager

Manage web development, graphic design and digital marketing projects from set-up to delivery for Biz Dev Now and it's clients; Source and hire freelancers. Expert WordPress set-up and maintenance. Graphic asset creation skills.

SmartsiteMovement, Aug 2012 - Sep 2014

Founder

Mobile -friendly websites for small businesses.

Market Analyst

Progressive Business Publications, Malvern, PA, Feb 2011 - Sep 2012

Manage email marketing campaigns for Fortune 500 to mid-sized companies. Revise marketing copy for struggling email marketing campaigns to improve lead generation results. Design landing pages and conduct newsletter updates on WordPress site.

FedSources, Washington, DC Metro, 2010 - 2011

Market Intelligence Analyst

Analyze and track federal government opportunities released by U.S. Navy agencies. Conduct in-depth internet and primary research for clients. Build professional relationships with Navy Contracting Officers. Attend industry conferences and publish reports for company website.

Help Unlimited Temps & Office Team, Washington, DC Metro, 2008 - 2009

Administrative Assistant

Temp Assignments:

DC Housing Finance Agency

Provide assistance to public regarding real estate buyer program and admin support to agency.

Giuliani Associates Architects Inc.

Data entry, AP/AR, payroll assistance, project folder maintenance

ComputerTraining.com, Newark, DE, 2007 - 2008

Assistant Director of Admissions

Conduct education sales for Microsoft Certification Program. Manage large database of potential students leads and schedule campus visits for Director of Admissions. Provide solid follow-up with potential students. Meet and exceed student enrollment goals.